the UAA is situated literally in the
middle of the 1040 window it is
basically situated in the middle of the
eastern hemisphere so you do have the
entire world that's come to this country
the locals themselves make up about 13%
of the population which is just
mind-blowing 87% are from around the
world God's drawing the nation's here
it's a nation of unreached peoples so
it's a strategic crossroads for the
gospel and it by God's grace has allowed
for evangelical Christians to be here
and to do ministry what if I meet
someone here that who comes from a
people group that have never heard the
gospel and maybe the one I reach today
tomorrow is the first one and maybe
they're the ones who have taken the
opportunity so right through that the
needier is for preachers of the gospel
romans 10
how will they call upon him whom they've
not heard how will they hear without a
preacher so there's a need for people to
come and preach the good news of the
Lord Jesus Christ
[Music]
you don't get these opportunities much
and if you don't take them you miss them
so we felt kind of that Mead and if the
Lord was in this that he would just open
the doors and he has we had no plan B
there's no no plan for after this we're
settling here and investing ourselves
here we are only here because the Lord
made it happen and so the things that
are happening are only because the
Lord's making them happen for seven or
eight years we've been training pastors
evangelists the Lord has really he's
moved among us over the years it's been
a true reform we're at people ask me why
here do by cos Craig price is here I
want to be where Jesus is and if that
means literally in the desert in the
wilderness sure all I'm really
encouraged by how the Lord's brought so
many graduates from Southern to come
here to serve in the ministry things
Southern is focused on good theology
lived out for the good of the nations
find its home here the Lord is at work
in this part of the world obviously it's
not making headline news but the Lord is
at work and he is building his church
we're in the midst of a revival here
there's more people coming to feed in
Africa and India and the Middle East
then there is an America the gospel is
speeding ahead you can go is more
worship for Jesus and more people
who have been saved and will be with us
on the last day