(music)
- Apocrypha comes from
a Greek word apokryphos,
which means to hide, what is hidden.
And the English word apocryphal
has come to mean false.
So when people talk about the Apocrypha,
as Protestants, as a
Protestant Evangelical,
I'm talking about additional books
that I don't believe
are part of the canon,
but additional books that
some Christian traditions,
like Catholicism, and Eastern Orthodoxy
include within their Old Testament canon.
There's no debate about the
content of the New Testament
among major Christian traditions.
It's as some people
have said, it's amazing
when you look at the diversity
and geographical spread,
and there's this affirmation
of the 27 book New Testament
canon that we have.
But depending on how you divide it up,
because there's portions
of books and so on,
whether it's 12 additional books,
or for Eastern Orthodoxy
there's even more.
Where did these books come from?
And why do Protestants
not believe they're part of the canon?
The easy explanation for this is to say
Jesus and the apostles didn't believe
this was part of the canon.
The Jews who wrote these books in the time
between the Old and New Testament
never included it in their canon,
they're not in the
synagogue that you go to,
they're not quoted as Scripture,
with as the Scripture
says, as Word of God says,
they're not quoted as
Scripture in the New Testament.
And so we don't believe that those
should be included within our canon.
The Apocrypha also contains
clear historical error,
unlike the Old and New
Testament Scriptures.
You can see lists of
these errors, for example
in Paul Wagner's book The Journey
from Text to Translations.
The Catholic Church, there
were certain regional councils
that affirmed books of the Apocrypha,
but a church-wide council
did not affirm the Apocrypha
as Scripture within the Catholic Church,
until the Council of Trent in 1546,
in reaction against the
Protestant Reformation.
So that should give us pause
if we don't have a church-wide
council affirming those books
until a reaction against Protestants.
And having said that, I
teach at a Baptist Seminary,
and so many times students who come
from the Baptist tradition
are very skeptical
about the Apocrypha,
they think it's almost
like an evil book, don't read it.
But I think that's wrong.
I mean these are books that
are written by early Jews
who were seeking to live a life,
many times pleasing to God,
there's a diversity within it,
but portions of the Apocrypha,
sound just like the Psalms,
calling out to God in
praise for His attributes.
There's a beautiful passage
in Sirach 38 about physicians,
that don't despise the physician,
pray to God for healing,
but don't be afraid to go to the physician
because God's given him wisdom
about the herbs of the Earth
and how they can heal you too.
So we read this and we think
this is people seeking to live,
to serve God many times,
I've always thought
the Book of Tobit would make
an amazing Disney movie.
It's not Scripture, but if
you read the Book of Tobit,
it has love, it has intrigue,
and it's really enjoyable
to read as a book, but it's not Scripture.
We can also when we read the Apocrypha,
it can help us understand what happened
between the last book of the Old Testament
and Jesus's ministry.
And where did these Pharisees come from?
Where did these Sadducees come from?
That story is told
really in the Apocrypha,
you read 1 and 2 Maccabees.
And so it gives us helpful
historical background.
Within the Protestant
tradition, I've found
that there are really two strands.
There's a strand that ends
up in sort of Anglicanism,
the English Church, and
then there's a strand
that's more like Baptist and Presbyterian,
and I guess Lutheranism would
be over here with Anglicanism,
and they will use words from the Apocrypha
for hymns and other things like that,
they don't believe it's Scripture.
But within the Baptist and
more Presbyterian tradition,
it's really only looked at as valuable
for historical background many times.
But if you look in your hymnal,
sometimes we even sing hymns
based on the Apocrypha,
but it usually doesn't
say that in our hymnal.
For example, the famous hymn
"Now Thank We All Our God"
which is in the Baptist hymnal,
is based on Sirach 50,
almost word for word,
this beautiful hymn to God.
Now thank we all our God, with
hearts and hands and voices,
who wondrous things has done,
in whom this world rejoices.
Or the famous Christmas carol
"It Came Upon a Midnight Clear"
is based upon a text out of the Apocrypha.
So the Apocrypha's not Scripture,
but it is helpful sometimes to understand
the things that happened
between the Testaments.
And some Christian
traditions have written hymns
and other things that use
some of the wording of the Apocrypha.
(music)
- [Narrator] Thanks for
watching Honest Answers.
Don't forget to subscribe.